Hello and welcome back to War Thunder Pages of History.
欢迎回到War Thunder Pages of History
A little while ago we told you the story of the M4 Sherman, the workhorse of the US tank court.
不久之前我们说了M4谢尔曼坦克——美国坦克部队主力的故事
This time let's talk about its British colleague, the A27,
现在我们来聊一下它的英国同僚A27
more commonly known as the Cromwell.
俗称克伦威尔
Let's start with the basics of the British tank classification.
让我们从英国坦克分类的基础知识讲起
Back to World War II, the British had cruiser and infantry tanks.
英国的二战坦克分为巡洋坦克和步兵坦克
Not the otherwise common types of medium and heavy tanks has handled by the rest of the world.
和世界上其他地方采用的更通常的中坦和重坦的分类不同
In battle our cruiser tank deals both with scaling and outflanking the enemy.
巡洋坦克负责在战斗中穿插包抄敌人
They mean characteristic of any cruiser tank is its speed.
意味着速度是任何巡洋坦克的特点
These machines have lighter armor and small caliber cannons
这些坦克有着更薄的装甲和<del>（咖喱棒）</del>口径更小的火炮
as they simply were not designed to engage in heavier enemy tanks in open combat.
因为在设计之初它们就不是用在开阔的战场上和敌军的重坦交战
A much heavier infantry tank on the other hand was designed to
更重的步兵坦克才负责与之交战
support the advancing infantry, engage in destroying the fortifications
而步兵坦克还支援推进中的步兵 破坏敌军的工事
and force the enemy infantry off their positions.
并击溃敌军的步兵
The speed was of little importance for an infantry tank
对步兵坦克而言 速度无所谓
so it allowed the designers to improve the armor since the immobility was not an issue.
因此当机动性不是问题时 设计者们就会增强它们的装甲
The A27 cruiser tank was developed to replace its lighter cousins the A15 and A25.
开发A27巡洋坦克是为了取代其较轻的表兄A15和A25
注：A15为Mk VI Crusader，即十字军巡洋坦克
总重
19.1吨至20.1吨
全长
5.97米（20尺8.5吋）
宽度
2.77米（9尺1吋）
全高
2.24米（7尺4吋）
Mk I/II:  成员4或5人（车长、炮手、装填手、驾驶员、机枪手）     武器为40毫米QF 2磅炮（110发）
Mk III:   成员3人（车长、炮手、驾驶员）     武器为57毫米QF 6磅炮（65发）
游戏中涉及到的型号有Crusader Mk.II和Crusader Mk.III
注：A25为Mk.VIII哈里·霍普金斯轻型坦克，用于取代A17/Mk.VII轻型坦克（A17/Mk.VII为游戏中的Tetrarch）
总重
19040磅（8.64吨）
全长
4.34m（14英尺3英寸）
宽度
2.65m（8英尺8英寸）
全高
2.11m（6英尺11英寸）
成员3人（车长，驾驶员，炮手）
武器为40毫米QF 2磅炮（50发）
But the military demanded heavier firepower in addition to improve the mobility.
但是军队既要更好的火力 也要更好的机动性
The designers knew that it was impossible to build a fast tank with truly good armor.
设计者们知道<del>（香港记者）</del>快速坦克是不可能装备厚实的装甲
But the order did that ask them for that anyway.
但是命令要求他们这么去设计
So the tank had rather lackluster armor mostly set at a right angle
所以坦克的装甲并不算好 而其中大多为垂直装甲
which was already considered a dinner cake design solution in 1942.
在1942年采纳了这种<del>（薄皮大馅）</del>晚宴蛋糕的设计方案
But despite that the British designers got it right.
尽管英国设计师思路没错
In 1942 to 43 the armor of even such outstanding tanks as T-34
1942年至43年即使如T-34那样具备出色装甲的坦克
could not effectively resist many kinds of enemy cannons
并不能有效抵御敌人的多种火炮
KwK 40 L/43（四号F2/G/H/J）、KwK 36 L/56（虎式）、 KwK 42 L/70（豹式）：我内心毫无波动，甚至还想笑
and was only considered proof against low caliber guns.
只能用来抵御小口径火炮
But the rationale sloping of the armor left little space inside the vehicle
但倾斜装甲留下的车内空间并不大
which drastically reduce the crew's comfort and ultimately its effectiveness.
这大大降低了乘员的舒适性 甚至影响到了成员的工作效率
Not to mention that having everything crammed and so closely together
更别说这坦克里的各种东西紧密地摆放在一起
make the tank a powder cake.
像粉饼一样脆弱
Knowing this the British chose a different solution.
知道了这一点 英国选择了不同的解决方案
They installed the armor at a right angle.
他们安装了垂直装甲
Having an irrational internal arrangement was more important than having an illusional armor.
不节约的内部空间安排要比疯狂的装甲更重要
So after suffering a penetrating hit the A27's crew simply had better chances of survival.
因此 在击穿之后 A27的成员生还几率显然更高
Weapon to wise the tank was equipped with a 6-pounder gun
提到武器 该坦克配备了6磅炮
which despite its modest caliber
尽管这是个<del>（谦虚）</del>偏小的口径
had a very high rate of fire and decent armor penetration qualities.
但是它射速高 穿深也不错
A large selection of ammunition available for it
还有许多弹药可供选择
allowed it to successfully engage and destroy even the toughest targets.
使这辆坦克能成功接近并摧毁即使是最坚固的目标
The cannon <del>leg got</del>（没听清……） an HE shell
这门炮高爆弹装药量少
which drastically decreased its application against enemy infantry.
这大幅降低了它对敌人步兵的应用
This was amended later on by installing a different cannon.
不过后来换装了另外一门炮之后得到了改进
注：这里指的应该是换装QF 75mm火炮
Both of these are really good weapons
这都是非常好的武器
or even further improved by the British setting mechanisms
英国甚至制定机制来进一步完善
which had a history of high quality long before the war.
其武器在战前就有着高品质的历史
By the way the first model of this tank
顺便一提 克伦威尔最初的版本
with an under-part of the engine was called the Centaur.
使用附属引擎的叫人马座
注：Centaur使用的是340马力的Liberty engine
Only when the tank got the state of the Rolls-Royce engine
只有那些装备了罗尔斯-罗伊斯引擎的
was increasing to Cromwell.
才升级为克伦威尔
Weighing just 27 tons while having 600 horsepowers
仅重27吨却拥有600马力
the Cromwell could go up to 40 miles an hour.
克伦威尔可以跑到40英里/小时（64.37千米/小时）的速度
The power to weight ratio of the tank was 27 horsepower per ton
推重比为每吨27马力
which was a record characteristic back in its day.
在当时算是创了纪录
The terrain crossing ability was the only major step leaving behind its famous Soviet counterpart.
越野能力可能是唯一被苏联同类坦克超越的部分
But not for lack of engine power.
但并不是由发动机马力不足造成的
The rather narrow tracks of the tank were to blame for that.
过窄的履带才是罪魁祸首
The A27 used the Christie suspension.
A27使用克里斯蒂悬挂
克里斯蒂悬挂：我还要飙一万年车
The very same that it was used on the T-34 and the A15 and the A25.
和T-34、A15还有A25所使用的很像
The British, however, had improved on the chassis quite considerably.
但是英国人在底盘上又加以细致的改进
This, usually the large part of the tank, was much smaller than its soviet colleague,
底盘常常是坦克中最大的部件 但英国人做的却比苏联人的小
The tank was rugged, reliable and easily serviceable
这辆坦克坚固可靠 易于维修
all while being smaller than most of its counterparts,
同时还能比大多数同类坦克较小
being only slightly larger than the earliest models of the T-34.
只比T-34的最初版本稍大
Later, the Cromwell's holy chassis were used to build a number of military utility vehicles.
后来 克伦威尔的强大底盘被用来建造一批军用车辆
Among them posted anti-aircraft mobile platform
图中的即是自行防空炮
注：根据维基，图中应为Centaur AA Mk II，采用Crusader III AA Mk III 的炮塔，武器为2x20mm厄利孔机炮
and a sold version of the tank with a 95mm howitzer
用于出售的95毫米榴弹炮
and the Cromwell Mk VW
还有克伦威尔Mk VW
in which the frontal hull and turret armor was upgraded to four inches.
其中正面车体和炮塔的装甲被升级到四英寸（101.6mm）厚
The model A27M was eventually replaced with the Comet.
而A27M最终被彗星取代
And upgraded version of the Cromwell with a new turret of 17-pounder gun,
彗星是克伦威尔的升级版 拥有17磅炮的新型炮塔
注：彗星使用的不是全尺寸的QF-17磅炮而是砍过倍径的77mmHV
the finest anti-tank cannon of the allies,
这是盟军中最好的反坦克炮
the A34 was considered the best tank of the Commonwealth and quite rightly so.
所以A34（即彗星坦克）被认为是英联邦最好的坦克也是理所当然的
It combined high-speed, a superb cannon, proven reliability and ease of use.
它结合了高机动性 极好的炮 身经百战的可靠性和易用性
The A34 is easily on part with T-34-85 or even the American M26.
A34可以与T-34-85 甚至美国的M26相媲美
The British engineers created a uniquely balanced machine.
英国的工程师们创造了一个特别平衡的坦克
Gaijin:我们的游戏特别平衡
The Cromwell of tanks had outstanding mobility, the good cannon.
克伦威尔拥有杰出的机动性 良好的火炮
It was rugged and easily produced to be common.
坚固且易于大量生产
The vehicle was well liked by cruised for its comfort and protection.
由于其对舒适性和安全的不懈追求
In so most of its combat action in Italy in France
在意大利和法国的大多数作战行动中 这辆载具广受好评
but ultimately did not become as well-known as the Soviet T-34 and the American Sherman.
不过最终还是没有苏联T-34和美国谢尔曼那样有名
which this video is still come for.
而T-34和谢尔曼则是我们以后要讲到的
This is it for today War Thunder Pages of History signing up.
今天的War Thunder Pages of History 到这就结束了